誒，亦都教柯林啦，我哋開會。
噉啊，首先請政府誒代表出席我哋個會議，同埋同時都叫埋啊嗰個。
社團嘅代表。
先，我啲觀念未到喎。
入緊嚟，請緊。
好，我哋開始。
嗱，請出席聽證會嘅代表，如果要帶上耳筒機咧，咁咧就要選擇頻道零咧，就話延長收收版一號咧就係廣東話，二號咧就英文，三號咧就普通話嘅啊。
咁大致上咧，嗰個每位嘅發言咧，我哋件事啊，定喺五分鐘啦。
噉我哋要提醒，即係誒全體嘅代表咧。
佢哋嘅發言同埋意見書咧，均不會受到咧立法會嘅權力及特權嘅條例嘅保障嘅。
咁亦都請佢哋留意喺立法會綜合大樓會議室出席會議或者公眾。
啊！席嘅旁聽嘅會議工作人士咧，必須之中。
各項保安措施。
而該須資以遏制。
嗰個秘書處發給嘅各位函件之中，並放喺各位嘅台上。噉啊，旁聽公眾人士亦都啊要向在場嘅立法會保安人索取有關嘅通知。
噉啊！提醒誒出席嘅代表，如果佢哋已經準備好發言稿咧，請佢哋喺發言稿上寫上姓名。稍後離開嘅時候，將發言稿交畀我哋嘅職員，讓委員會作為一個參考。
噉。
而家我哋請阿雷若韓先生。
誒，發表意見。
Thank you very much.
Please excuse me. Speaking in English.
嗯。
The Hong Kong Venture Capital Association, who I'm representing, has requested some changes to the the law from the point at which the original offshore funds tax exemption was brought out in in 2007.
And over the last two or three years, we we've worked very closely with the Financial Services and Treasury Bureau, who have understood many of the issues, most of the issues that we we have raised, and have been very cooperative in producing a a draft.
law that we think is very effective for the private equity community. So I will make just five comments on, in addition to the paper that has been submitted to the members.
The first comment is that private equity.
是實際playing a very small role in the financial services community here. We do not employ a lot of people. There are perhaps two or three thousand people directly employed by private equity in Hong Kong.
But whilst it isn't a huge number, we generate a significant amount of other opportunity for the financial sector in Hong Kong. That over the last five years, more than thirty percent of all IPOs on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange have had private equity investors, and.
We provide a lot of business opportunities to investment bankers, to the accounting and legal profession, to fund administrators, so that the multiplier effect of our activity is quite considerable. And the 110 billion dollars of capital under management.
Management in Hong Kong generates a lot of fee activity for the rest of the financial services community.
The second point is that the private equity industry in Hong Kong.
是Ranked in about in the top three or four private equity communities in the world. It is a very substantial and leading-edge part of the private equity world.
And when you look at the opportunity in Asia for new investment and the track record of private equity investment in Asia to date,
There is a very good grounds to believe that the industry has got plenty of room for further growth, and that Hong Kong should be the centre for a lot of that growth in the future. So we are cutting edge and strong, and we need to develop only slightly to be successful.
The third point is that.
Over the last few years, there have been pressure for structural change to offshore funds.
Across the whole fund industry, so mutual funds, hedge funds and private equity funds, all have reasons to believe that coming to Hong Kong.
And bringing funds on shore important to their business, and for the private equity industry, it is driven by the fact that we can invest through double tax treaties into countries where we want to put our money to work. Hong Kong has a good but not excellent range of double tax treaties.
But is where we have our presence already. And the issue under double tax treaties that has started to impact firms is that for the destination countries such as China or India or Australia or South Korea.
They will give benefit to firms investing into their countries, where there is substance at the
國籍起源，和，到而家喺香港，我哋都冇能夠有，好大嘅實質，因為我哋只能夠從香港提供建議，而我哋又唔能夠將資金帶入香港。我哋喺未來想嘅係，能夠喺香港有資金同經理人。
所以你有自然的 substance，支持著税惠，我們希望給投資者。
The fourth point is that.
Despite there being a a real reason why people have chosen to put their key management personnel of PE firms into Hong Kong.
the those firms have had to create complicated structures to avoid there being management activity from Hong Kong. That they through inside a firm you have processes to make sure that you advise only and do not step over the line and take management.
因為，因為
and with this new legislation, we think that the efficiency will improve considerably in the way firms can operate in Hong Kong. So people will be very happy with that. So to conclude, we're strongly supportive of the changes that are proposed in this bill.
which will make for greater efficiency of the PE operations that are already based in Hong Kong.
which we believe will generate additional tax revenue as those firms undertake more activities and therefore will pay larger amounts of profit tax on their activities here.
which will encourage new firms to come and be based in Hong Kong in the future, and which we don't think will have any impact of losses of taxation because we don't think in the private equity sphere there are offshore funds that are today paying tax because they're managed from Hong Kong that will then.
Avoid paying tax under this new legislation. So, in conclusion, we are very, very supportive of the proposals that are being made here. Thank you.
Okay.
噉啊！我哋想請政府對於啊雷若韓先生誒嘅講話有咩回應咧？
嗯，多謝主席，亦都好高興今日啊，可以啊，同啊業界咧，亦特別係香港啊創業同埋私募投資協會啊交流意見。我哋正如頭先啊雷先生所講咧，我哋喺過去一年多兩年嘅時間咧啊，就住呢個議題，其實。
實都有唔少交換意見。誒，我哋好高興今日我哋能夠真係將一個誒草案嘅條例啊係好實在咁交畀呢個誒法案委員會去研究。我哋背後，我頭先都好誒同意啊，雷先生嘅一個一啲睇法。
同埋而家，誒，佢喺作為一個業界人士，佢點樣睇啊？私募基金喺香港發展嗰個勢頭，特別係佢指出咧。誒，私募基金雖則喺而家現有佢啊聘用嘅人員喺數字上或者唔係咁多，但係誒。
私募基金喺香港嚟講係作為一個非常之高增值嘅一個行業，佢啊喺我哋啊利用香港嗰呢個金融嘅平台，包括嗰我哋嗰個誒基金誒去誒上市，作為一個好好平台，係一個好大嘅證明香港嗰個潛力。
誒，正如頭先啊，阿雷先生所講咧，我哋而家喺業誒區內，亦其實誒做得亦都唔錯。但係誒，正如業界指出咧，而家嗰個税誒務嘅條例係有啲唔清晰嘅地方，以致到佢哋可能喺運作嘅時候需要做好多繁瑣嘅程序。
嚟到啊，係令到個業務更加喺税收上有一個肯定性。今日我哋經過誒誒過去十幾個月同業界商量咗之後咧，今日我哋誒作出嘅一啲所謂税務嘅修訂咧，特別係針對離岸私募基金嘅一啲誒。
豁免啊，利息嗰個啊誒誒嗰個利得税嘅豁免咧，嗰個機制咧，希望係誒一方面咧係能夠切合即係業界嗰個需要同埋需求，令到佢哋啊可以喺實際上咧有一個機制可以誒明確噉啊可以就。
得益喺嗰個税務豁免方面，而另一方面，我哋喺啊税收方面咧，亦都係能夠誒保障確啊，能夠咧唔會有好大即係有濫用嗰個情況，或者一啲流動嘅噉，所以我哋相信今日我哋喺啊條例草案。
嗰度係啊一啲建議咧，包括一啲所謂符合啊符合資格嘅基金啊，誒嗰啲有啲要求啊，都係過往我哋啊誒年多以嚟咧，同業界都有好大嘅即係一個討論咧。咁而定定嘅，我哋就誒覺得而家嗰個建議咧，都係取得咗一個。
平衡總的嚟講咧，我哋都好誒高應業界能夠即係係支持呢個法案啦。誒都希望能夠早日落實誒，以致到咧佢哋能夠係嚟到利用香港。正如頭先好似雷先生咁講咧，繼續發展咧香港作為一個誒私募基金嘅一個樞紐，即係話誒。
誒利用香港呢一個平台，能夠聘請更多我哋嘅專業人士去管理我哋啲基金啦，以至用香港作為一個平台咧，去投資喺誒世界各地嘅一啲啊私募嘅即係誒公司上面。
啊，主席或者我。
我我哋都希望咧，政府喺會議之後咧，盡量將嗰啲填提代表嘅發表嘅意見咧，提供一個書面嘅回應畀我哋委員作為參考啦。
噉啊，睇睇我哋嘅委員有冇誒邊個要發言？我哋時間係有啊，首輪咧五分鐘啦。啊，第一個啊，梁繼昌議員。
不好意思，Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Mr. Lavac, I understand that the industry generally welcomes the direction of the proposed.
印度 Revenue Amendment Bill， which gives profits tax exemption for certain types of private equity offshore private equity funds investing in private companies。
And of course, I mean this is quite quite a technical bill. And in your view, and I understand that you have been involved with the discussion on the detail proposals of the bill. But is there any technical amendments which you think the the
Government could have done better in in terms of this draft, and if you do have a view on that, could you please let us know what what what is your view on the more technical side of this bill, please?
Ask for everything, which we we know we can't get. So, the the bill is very good. In terms of the implementation of it, one of the key elements will be.
The IRD's practice notes as to how matters will be treated in detail, which is a further discussion that I'm sure we will have with the IRD. And the relationship with IRD is very strong, so we hope that that will be a constructive process. In terms of
The the two things that we would really have liked to have seen included in the the bill that are not there as it stands. The first is that the the the way it is structured is that it allows an offshore fund to invest.
Anywhere but in Hong Kong.
and the implication of that, as we take it at the moment, is that if you make a Hong Kong investment, it containts the whole of the the tax benefit for the fund. and on the whole, we believe that private equity
Investment can be good for the companies that we invest in. That it is putting new money into those companies, and often it is to allow those companies to expand and add more jobs and to develop.
And we think that Hong Kong should be encouraging private equity to invest in those Hong Kong companies, rather than making it difficult.
從我們的側面，我們會強烈prefer法案説，如果你們從離岸基金投資到香港公司，那麼這筆投資會按香港對離岸投資的正常方式徵税。
But the rest of the fund be allowed to be untainted by that investment, so that if you typically have 15 investments and one or two of those is in Hong Kong, then those shouldn't affect the 13 odd that are remaining outside. And for it to be clear, so that is.
是第一樣，我們認為會對香港好。我們明白有爭議，關於這個制度是否會被濫用，這是金融管理局和IRD的擔憂。我們希望看到這個制度被取消，投資被允許。
in Hong Kong companies, and I would stress that this would also apply to venture capital, and Hong Kong has quite a dynamic, young entrepreneurial IT-related sector at the moment, which
is going to need capital, and if the the venture capital firms that participate with using offshore funds are going to find it difficult to invest in Hong Kong, that is going to be a cost to Hong Kong. So, so that is the first technical detail that we would raise. The second
是，那。
香港是發展作為一個基地。
big。
multinational investors such as sovereign wealth funds, such as some of the large pension funds and some state-owned enterprises, particularly Chinese state-owned enterprises, which do not qualify as qualifying funds because.
Don't have at least six investors, despite the fact that they they encompass many many individuals' interests. And if there was a technical way that those could be included, that would be a great benefit as well. Because as a centre, Hong Kong really benefits from those people.
選擇要基於他們的運作。
Thank you.
誒，莫禮公園。
主席，Mr. Levick， actually I'm not sure whether you might have answered part of my question in your previous answer. But but I might have been a little bit not paying attention, and I'm not sure whether I caught exactly what that is. But essentially.
my question was that when I when during the first meeting of this subcommittee
I actually raised a concern that because the the current arrangement is such that you the government is proposing to
to provide tax exemption, further tax exemption for funds that are investing in offshore activities or offshore companies. Of course, we understand that that is going to be very helpful for the development of the financial services industry and the funding and the fund asset management or fund management company.
And that industry and so on. But of course, there are, as you know, that the government is right now trying to also develop the technology and IT and entrepreneurial activities in Hong Kong. And there was, I expressed a bit of concern whether or not this would attract more.
資金 to be invested offshore because of this reason, and in in in a way, not becoming very not going to be very helpful for the local companies, local entrepreneurs that are actually looking for funds and finding it rather difficult at the moment because of our.
relatively immature or not as well developed as we like to see as as far as the venture capital market is concerned. So I wonder if you can share your views about whether that would really be the case.
Or or it is not exactly a problem at all. Would would you believe that that is actually a problem, or would you rather see that local activities are also exempted? Of course, that would be that might be going a little bit too far. I don't know as far as the tax regime is.
Concerned, but what do you think this sort of change may entice more funds to actually go out of Hong Kong rather than being invested in local companies?
That's a very good question. I didn't address it properly in my first answer.
If this bill gets passed as it stands, and if I'm now able to be a manager here,
The consequence of the bill.
是， that it is easier for me to direct my capital offshore into a non-Hong Kong business than it is for me to direct it into a Hong Kong business, which is a very strange outcome.
嗯。
And as an association, we we like you believe that there is is a real opportunity to support the entrepreneurialism of of Hong Kong that is is growing nicely at the moment, but is still small and is going to need capital.
my colleagues who are much more technically proficient than I am in the industry tell me that if you want to invest from your offshore fund into a Hong Kong entity.
There are ways in which you could structure it, effectively create another vehicle of the fund outside in the Cayman, and that would then invest into a Hong Kong company, and the rest of the fund would be invested outside, and you would then have a different relationship.
with that Cayman entity which was investing in Hong Kong, where you would only advise it again.
所以， we go back to the circumstances of playing this split between advising and managing， such that we're a creative industry. We will pay quite a lot of fees to advisers to allow us to do what we want to do.
但 part of the purpose of this amendment is to to make to simplify and make easier the investment of offshore funds by managers based in Hong Kong, and for investments in Hong Kong it will be complicated again for us. So we can still do it.
但係，它會 not have the benefit of the simplification that is coming through today， which is an irritation rather than damaging the purpose.
Our view is is that you could address that by saying that an investment in a Hong Kong company is allowed.
但係，outside of the benefit of this，但係，它唔會汙染到基金嘅其他部分。
The the FSDB is concerned about abuse possibilities there, but.
要簡化答案，yes， we could still invest in in Hong Kong companies, but it's harder than investing in a Chinese company.
主席，我繼續跟進定係再排過？
係。
應該我可以繼續跟進定係再排？嗰個我諗睇下有冇第一輪嘅議員要提意見嘅。如果冇咧，我哋進入第二輪啦。咁第二輪咧，誒嗰個梁繼昌議員啦。
啊！
哦，Thank you, Mr. Chairman. In fact, I would like the the government to respond to to to this point raised by Mr. Blevack about the tainting of a qualified fund. Because what I get from from you is that if an offshore fund, if part of the offshore fund, no matter how how much, I think
I think that's a minimum the minimum threshold. Invest in a Hong Kong private company, then the whole of the fund would be automatically disqualified from being an eligible offshore fund to be entitled to the
profits tax exemption under this regime is my understanding correct? But I don't see the rationale because if
Only say about fifteen percent of the whole fund is investing a passive investor in a Hong Kong company. Why? Why should the whole this fifteen percent of investment taint the whole fund and thereby resulting in the whole fund being disqualified from being an eligible fund? Mr. Chairman, I think I would like the.
The government to give a reply to that.
政府。
嗯。
If I may, I will answer this question again in Chinese perhaps, but just for the sake of John, I think we've discussed this issue time and again during our.
exchange of views over the past year or so. I understand the the concern and and and the the demand of industry. Again.
We would like to do the most for the industry, as John put it at the beginning of this meeting.
Yet on the other hand, we do need to consider any possibility for abuse or leakage of of taxation revenue for that proposal.
So again, back to the key point is there are two points that we are concerned about. It may venture into a bit of technicality that I would perhaps seek the assistance of Mr. Chiu from R&D to explain later on. But the two two major
Points here is the risk of of offshore funds seeking to redomesticate.
and become offshore funds, and enjoy the tax benefit.
which may not be difficult to do so if we allow the situation that John just mentioned, that within a fund, a certain element, a portion of it is allowed to invest into.
Hong Kong companies or make investment to Hong Kong, then our the in their practical experience consider that that may not be something very difficult to do so.
The second consideration is that the the definition of a non-resident
which is now the the key point of this.
regime would include not only funds but also natural persons. So that that are these are two major angles that would make the the the way that can we can devise a scheme to cater.
for what the industry is asking, very difficult. We we will keep considering it, but then it will be quite a difficult task to achieve. Having the two points, if I may just recapture that a little bit in Chinese, is that
誒，我哋認為，如果容許誒，
有誒喺呢個所謂誒離岸基金下邊，有部分係可以即係投資喺香港嗰啲啊公司，誒而又受受到一啲即係。
啊！誒，税務上面嘅一啲誒所謂嗰個規則咧，去誒作出豁免，或者係需要誒交税嗰個誒分嘢係唔容易做嘅。誒同埋咧誒，主要因為誒而家非居港啊嘅誒嗰個。
人士嘅定義係好闊，係包括任何人、自然人啊，基金都會包括。另外一方面，我哋就係嗯，税局方面喺佢日常行事嘅時候，認為啊，都容易就造成一啲流動，特別係而家啊，已經係喺香港註冊嘅基金或者居民，佢誒可以。
以用一啲方法變成一啲非居港註冊嘅居民或者基金咧，以致係享受到依一啲所謂嘅誒。
啊！益處噉，所以基於呢兩點嘅考慮咧，我哋係啊認為而家嗰個做法係取得一定嘅平衡。
或者睇下阿阿梁繼昌有冇回應啊？
誒，我好長，我諗畀阿莫乃光講先，我再跟進，我第三輪啊嘛。O.K.第三輪啊，莫乃光語，莫乃光，莫乃光語。唔該主席。啊，well，actually，I would like to follow up with Mr. Levick about your your reply， your respond to my question。
First of all, it's great to hear that you know the local fund investment industry would be interested in supporting local industry, local companies and so on. But I did hear from your respond that you think that you know some of your more technical colleagues had been saying that there might be ways to you know.
sort of in a way get around the the the whole thing by you know investing in a local company that might be I mean through a different ways of various ways of arrangement that they might be you know the the investment target might be a Cayman Island company but in in in the end you know part of the operation or whatever would actually
Actually, be a Hong Kong company. Now, if that's the case, I wonder if the administration would actually consider that to be a loophole. First of all, and second, you know, is there a more proper way to to to that you would suggest for this particular bill to handle that sort of situation? Because I mean, at least from my point of view, from
what where I'm coming from, what I would like to see is that, you know, we're not drawing money funds that are in Hong Kong, because of this particular test tax benefit reason to be invested outside of Hong Kong, which which to me is only helping the maybe.
The fund managers, that industry, but doesn't help the rest of Hong Kong's economy.
香港是個開放經濟，和鼓勵外資投資，和，有效地，如果一外資
entity， be it a person or or a corporate or a limited partnership， makes an investment in a Hong Kong company， and holds that investment for a number of years， which is in our case typically three to seven years， and then sells it。
our
supposition is that it would be then taxable in Hong Kong just as any foreign investment should be taxed and we would make a claim that that should be treated as a capital gain because a long-term investment held for three to seven years and then sold is pretty much what
capital gain is.
and there is a zero rate of of tax on capital gains. So, in in terms of the the tax treatment, Hong Kong is is actually quite beneficial to a foreign entity investing in it, and and what this
change in the the.
The exemption does is it just means you you structure it as a foreign investment rather than part of your your fund, which is introduces some complexity but is not a major problem for a firm to do. It would
In our view, be be simpler to allow it to be part of the fund, and tax each investment as Hong Kong sees fit to tax it, without tainting the rest of the fund.
But it's not my job to defend Hong Kong from the loopholes that I may not be aware of. So I I can't argue on the the technicalities with the I R D on that.
會，主席，May I actually also ask the administration whether they would consider this sort of arrangement to be proper?
I mean the the ones that Mr. Leavitt talk about that you know investing in a probably a foreign vehicle, but in but you know.
It may have to do with ultimately a Hong Kong company operating in Hong Kong.
哦，喺呢方面政府有咩意見啊？
嗯。
So I would invite Mr. Chiu to respond to that because I think we will not venture into case-specific comments, but I think it's general.
yes。
Thank you, Chairman. Maybe I say a few words about the example mentioned by John.
now, now basically under the offshore fund regime for private equity funds, the offshore private fund can only be allowed to invest in companies, private companies, not doing business in Hong Kong and not holding any Hong Kong immovable properties. This is
基本 idea。
now，the question is whether you can structure your your fund in such a way that you can do other business. I think it all depends on the facts of each case. Now I think it's very a
it wouldn't it would not be too appropriate for me to jump into a certain conclusion saying whether a particular structuring of the investment is
proper or not proper, it all depends at the end of the day how the terms of the agreement is being draft, how the structuring is being done. I think these are factual issue and depends on the facts of each case.
仲有冇語言有問題嘅？
啊，梁繼昌。No， I I just want to follow up one one point mentioned by the administration in my previous question.
Talking about you know not allowing any offshore fund to to invest in Hong Kong portfolio, because one of the drawbacks identified by the Inland Revenue is that if the bill does allow an offshore fund to invest in a Hong Kong
private company or Hong Kong portfolio， the administration one of the you know concern is that for the funds already operating or established in Hong Kong， it would trigger off a trend of these fund to redot missile in into another
jurisdiction is that one of your your your concern? It's the first concern you raised. Is that correct?
yeah。
Yes, but we will not say it will trickle off. But there is the possibility and risk that that they they they can allow such an option to exist.
I think that that's my response.
But I cannot see in real real situation that that that you know is the case because.
If the Hong Kong domiciled funds can be easily redomiciled in another jurisdiction, they would do so. And the chance that a offshore fund investing in Hong Kong, you know, companies getting taxed, I think, in reality, is quite low as long as they get the structure.
correct。
that that is my my personal experience as well, so I don't see a real leakage here. I think maybe the government is being
to you know prudent in structuring this bill, that is my comments. But of course.
I I don't think I can persuade you to listen to my you know my friend here in the industry to to provide another you know.
more user-friendly draft, but I I I do want the committee here to to take down this point, and the other point which I think many many many of us have mentioned, not just the honourable Charles, not just Mr. Lewac.
is that that there must be a regime I think in maybe your next wave of legislation to allow funds to invest passively in Hong Kong startup companies and get
唔好。
the same type of you know tax exemption.
Because this is only good for for the long-term development of startups in Hong Kong. I'm not talking about running business in Hong Kong, that which is quite clearly you know a separate case. But if you got funds investing passively in Hong Kong offshore funds.
Done. I I do not know why. Of course, I mean you you may tell me. I I had this conversation with the administration before that there is not enough time at this juncture to consider such a big piece of legislation. But I do think it would only be beneficial to Hong Kong. And I think the legislators across the spectrum would agree.
這這 type of exemption。
是necessary in order to diversify the economic economic base of Hong Kong, and I want also this point to be you know taken into to record and and maybe the administration can have a brief response as well.
O.K.，秘書長，有冇意見嚇？
We note the views of the honourable Kenyatta. As we we explained before, to do so would incur quite a wide ranging sort of policy sort of implications and considerations. We would of course also
attach a lot of importance and actually emphasis on developing the, for example, the startups industry in Hong Kong. And members may be aware that even in the in the recent budget announced by the financial secretary, there has been injection of funds to
sponsoring startups in Hong Kong, if I remember correctly, there's five.
billions to that amount in into supporting the development of startups in in Hong Kong. So there are many means. Meanwhile, we have also been seeing investment into startups firms in Hong Kong, whether it's in the fintech area or other area. Of course, taxation is an an
measure or something that can be facilitative, but given the wide ranging implications of the the idea mentioned by the honourable, we will have to consider it in far greater detail. So that's why we are proposing to take.
the present proposal forward first, and then in the longer run to consider other options.
好，仲有冇議員要提問嘅？
啊。
阿雷若寒先生，有冇其他意見？
I think my my conclusion is that what we have is a big step forward, and
I'm not sure in this chamber, I should say, but we we are inclined to pocket it, but.
嗯。
係。
But, what I would like to emphasise is that.
As a little sector of the financial services world, we we have a further ask that that we we want to put on the table, which is that we have funds brought onshore here, and I think that is more of an important issue than this one. We are we have.
already been discussing this with the administration and getting positive feedback, and and my sense is that there should be another opportunity soon to address this issue as part of a wider picture. And if we have that understanding, I'm I'm very much encouraged that we can get it right. That we can.
make sure that there is a good access to the offshore capital for Hong Kong businesses and Hong Kong startups and entrepreneurs. And my inclination would be to say let's move ahead with this now, and at the next round, make sure that we find the right way to accommodate.
Hong Kong companies accessing offshore capital in a sensible way.
好，如果冇。
係，語言有大啲意見，我哋結束呢個時段啦。噉啊，今日都好多謝阿雷耀韓先生，即係出席我哋呢個誒聽證會啦。咁亦都希望咧，如果雷生有進一步嘅意見咧，都可以咧向我哋委員會提交進一步。
嘅預見，用我哋去去參考嘅。
噉啊！
暫時咧，我哋可以請啊雷生離開呢個會議室，我哋繼續。
唔該。
好，我哋。
我哋繼續跟進二零一五年四月二十八號會議席上提出嘅議嘅事項。
噉啊！長情在於立法會C.B.括一八四九，縮一四。
一或十五括號零二嘅文件。
並於二零一五年五月十五號已經係發畀個委員嘅啦。
噉啊！請政府啊，作一個簡單嘅報告。
誒多謝主席。誒或者頭先我哋誒個文件咧，就係誒誒同剛才嗰個討論都其實有好多係誒重複嘅地方，或者係誒都有誒觸及啦。誒包括就係我哋而家香港啊喺誒私募基金管理方面嗰個情況啦。
誒，我哋誒睇到咧，香港而家喺誒管理私募基金個總資本值咧，誒喺區內咧都誒誒擺誒喺前列嘅位置，啊係喺誒內地之後。咁而家二零一四年底咧，係誒管理緊大概係百分之二十或者二十一左右嘅。
嘅資產值嘅咁咁誒，其他啊方面點解係啊要係有誒現時嗰個建議，即係話係釐清離岸私募基金嗰個啊情況咧？我諗剛才個討論都係有啊相當嘅誒深入去。
誒誒講及講及啊！我喺依度就唔啊唔重複，或者我哋可以睇一睇喺即係逐條審議嘅時候，有啲技術性嘅問題，我哋亦都係可以一並去答覆嘅嚇。
好啦，嗰個政府當局已就法律顧問喺二零一五年嘅五月四號咧嘅信函中提出嘅問題，立法會嘅C B佢回一八四九一四一或十五零三嘅文件之中作出嘅回應。立法會C B佢回一八四九一。
一四至一五嗰度零四號嘅文件，委員會可就嗰個討論有關方面嘅文件。
啊，邊位議員？
要發言嘅請舉手啦！我咧都係有五分鐘，我啲時間就比較充裕嘅。
如果大家冇繼續誒提問嘅議題，我哋。
好啊。
楊繼昌議員，啊，主席，你可唔可以請呢個誒政府當局解釋翻佢喺就誒我哋法律顧問嘅五月四號封信嘅啊Clause Eight嗰個嗰個回覆嗰個理據，Clause Five我就冇乜。
個問題就close eight嗰度，可唔可以請佢解解釋一下咧？嗰個嗰個答案嚇。
就。
係，主席，或者我請阿趙生嚇誒解釋一下。
誒，多謝主席。就第cross八嗰度講緊嘅咧，就一個技術上嘅用語，就叫做英文就叫做bond fund wide held嘅。簡單嚟講咧，就呢個呢個液液體咧，就簡單嚟講，嗰個基金咧係畀。
誒好多人持有嘅個觀念上係嗱原因，因為我哋嗰個有一個叫做反避有一個即係個針對性嘅避反避税嘅地方位置嘅，就話如果呢個海外基金呢個非居港者基金offshore翻。
有一個香港嘅居民。
多過三成嘅話。
咁即使個海外基金免咗税。
噉。
嗰個香港居民佔翻嗰部分嘅利潤咧，都要徵翻交翻香港税。呢個一個我哋技術上嘅用語就係驚一個香港人透過一個海外基金就達到一個免税嘅行為嘅。咁喺呢個大前提之下咧，噉就有一個甜文嘅，就就可以咁講喺個。
避避險嘅講嘅。
就如果係話，如果嗰個基金係實際上係一個好大誒好多人士持有嘅，咁雖然佢多過三十，我哋都覺得呢個針對性嘅反避税嘅條文都唔用唔著㗎。咁至於呢個技術上嘅用語、英語上係bondify wide。
係點嘅意思咧？咁其實我哋就係喺執行嘅指引裏邊，税務局嘅有兩張執行指引，分別係二十同四十三咧，都有解釋過呢個意思嘅。簡單嚟講，嗰個基金點話係大部分持有就係講緊喺任何時候都唔少於有五十個，或者用一個。
術語就係投資者噉樣啦。另外一點咧，就係話唔會喺任何時間有少過二十一個人操控誒，大概大七十五個percent嘅資本或者收入嘅咁呢個基金就被認為係bonded fund，wildly held。噉就我哋會認同唔係一個。
避税嘅行為。
咁至於法律顧問提出話有冇需要進就呢個技術性嘅條文嚟作出喺法例作出解釋咧？我哋税務局嘅立場就係話，其實呢個用語咧，其實已經係用咗好多年㗎啦，唔係一個新嘅技術嘅用語。咁亦都喺税務局嘅執行指引用咗多年嘅。咁所以我哋嘅睇法就。
就話未未有一個需要，需要喺法例上重申下一個定義啊！
明白，但但係即係話咧，如果你嗰個基金係真正財產權分散，即係幫到wide wide help咧，就算嗰個人有三十percent嘅時候咧，你都唔會apply呢個dimming provision，呢個係咪我嘅理解咧？嗱，呢個當然係同不拉。
收嗰個二零零六年嗰個海外嘅，即係海外基金嗰個豁免條例一樣嘅嗰個精神。咁但係點解？即係其實我睇到，就算你話幫得翻啲wildly held，但係嗰個人的確有三十percent of嗰個分嘅時候，我又睇唔到點解你要。
豁免佢就話佢唔係roundtripping呢樣嘢，我都覺得有有點而即係。
奇怪咯，即係即係我唔係太明，佢始始終都有三十percent嘅interest喺度，係咪？
啊，趙生，誒，主席，咁當二零零六年嗰時設計呢個離岸基金嘅嘅法例咧，其實當日考慮一個實際嘅環境嘅，就係話雖然個基金係離岸嘅，作為一個投資者咧。
如一個普通嘅投資者講，我佢好難判斷到自己嗰個比比重係幾多，因為個比重我哋有時多有時少嘅。其實個條文嘅設計係正我頭先解釋就係一個針對性嘅避税嘅條文嚟嘅。咁如果個事實睇出嚟，呢個基金本身唔係。
唔滿足人係去必需嘅，咁所以就一個明顯講畀佢點解嘅啫。
嗯，有冇跟進啊梁姨？
暫時冇啦，唔該，主席。其實有冇其他誒議員要發言嘅？
咁如果冇咧？
我哋咧就誒。
開始，我哋草案嘅逐項條文嘅審議好冇？
啊！政府唔該。
係，或者我請阿何女士啊。
誒多謝主席。誒或者我建議咧，誒利用誒秘書處誒提供誒預備咗嗰個誒標明文本嗰度誒，我嚟做個介介紹啊！
咁喺誒標明文本嘅第一頁，噉就係關於二十A B條嘅修訂嘅二十A B條咧，其實就係離岸基金嘅税項豁免制度相關條文嘅釋義。噉我哋今次嘅係誒呢個修訂咧，係喺標題嗰度同埋喺第一款有關適用範圍裏邊咧，加入新增有關將税務項豁免法。
範圍新延到離岸私募基金嘅相關條文嘅。
咁跟住嚟咧，就係誒標明文本嘅第二同第三頁啦。咁呢度主要其實都係二十A B條第四同第五款描述任何人被視為對另一人享有直接同埋間接實益權益嘅情況，為二十A E同A F條嘅推定條文作適宜嘅。咁因為我哋今次呢個嚟。
按私募基金呢個税項豁免嘅制度，亦都誒將呢個特定目的工具誒都可以響誒響呢個税務豁免嘅。咁而特定目的工具咧，其實除咗可以以法團啦、合夥啦、信託產業誒誒嘅方式成立之外，亦都可以以其他實體形式成立。咁所以我哋今次就建議係加入第四。
D同埋第五D段嘅。
繼續咧，係啊，接住落嚟咧，係第四頁啦。咁呢度就係講二十A C條。二十A C條咧，其實就係定明離岸基金獲得税項豁免需要符合嘅條件。噉我哋建議修訂第二款，定明咧進行指明交易嘅離岸基金，只要符合以下其中一行條件。
咧就已經有資格獲得税項豁免嘅噉。第一咧就係指明交易係透過指明人士，即係證監會嘅持牌法團啦進行，或者由指明人士安排進行。噉我哋今次特別再加咗另一個條件咧，就係有關非港居港者係屬於符合資格嘅基金。
咁另外，我哋喺第四頁嗰度睇到啦。我哋另外加咗第五B款啦，表明經修訂後嘅條文咧，係適用於二零一五年四月一號至到修訂條例生效前嘅一日期間進行嘅交易。依個咧係其實係一個過渡性嘅條文。噉我哋將日期定於一五年四月一號咧，係配合貨誒貨税年度。
每年咧係由四月一日起計嘅。
啊，梁繼昌議。
啊！主席，我問一問咧，二十A C條誒。
二B Roman七一同二嗰個點解會係？
以下條件符合其中一項，唔係兩個條件都要符合嘅咩？我我我我冇睇錯，因為我我理解錯咗咧。
係，誒主席，誒其實係誒其中一行嘅，因為而家我哋今次嗰個誒誒條例個修訂，其中有一個收到業界嘅消誒嘅誒反應咧，就係有啲私募基金其實係未必需要有誒由依個證監會持持牌法團，即係依度所講嘅指明人士進行嘅，咁所以我哋今次。
為咗誒誒方便業界嗰個運作，特別定明另一項條件咧，就係有關非居港者屬於符合資格嘅基金，亦都可以得到豁免。噉我哋後邊嘅條文誒，其實嚟緊我都會介紹呢個所謂誒符合資格基金係要符合咩條件先可以做到嘅。唔係唔係，但係我我係咪即係其實嗰個最主要條件就？
就係一個qualified fund，然之後咧個non-resident person。誒，仲要係二A佢係做一個係個指明交易。第二誒，首先當然佢係一個非居港者啦。第二佢要做個二A係一個誒指明交易。咁然後二B嘅一或者二。
但係一我唔係好明點解會係正即係二B嘅一或者二唔係就係二B二已經夠啦。其實即係如果噉樣，你唔都唔使即係即係。如果你係一個qualify offshore fund non-resident person，其實qualify分二你做一個指明交易，咁咁已經係符合呢個條件啦。因為我我。
我唔明點解會而誒，即係個B一Roman One個Concession has been carried out through arranged by specified person呢？呢呢個。
即係呢樣嘢點解會冇無端端加咗落去嘅咧？誒，主席，其實二B一係現有條文嚟嘅，因為我哋其實依個喺零六年已經有呢個税務豁免㗎嘛，嚇，咁所以係貨誒現有，譬如對沖基金或者其他基金咧，佢哋都可以用指名人士。O K O K，得明白明白。
好，我哋繼續。
係。
誒噉，然後咧誒去到第五至到十二頁誒裏邊，其實都係就呢個二誒二十A C條裏邊嘅主要定義作咗解釋嘅。咁好似頭先咁講啦，所謂符合資格基金喺第十頁嗰度咧，我哋做咗個定義嘅。咁定義咧，其實就係反映咗私募基金嘅典型特色，係即係話佢哋係屬於一
一個集體投資嘅工具，誒，即係有多名投資者嘅投資工具，而唔係只係由基金管理公司與有誒擁有絕大多數嘅權益嘅工具。噉，所以我哋喺誒條文裏邊規定咧，要符合誒做呢個符合資格嘅基金咧，首先佢需要喺權益出售最終截止日之後，有至少五名嘅。
投資者另外咧，由投資者作出嘅資本認繳咧，係要佔總額嘅百分之九十嘅。咁另一個條件咧，就係呢個基金嘅交易所產生嘅淨收益裏邊，由有關發起人同發起人相聯者收取部分減去，因為呢啲發起人同埋呢相聯者自己投放資本嘅部分之後咧，佢哋唔可以。
收到超誒超越淨收益嘅百分之三十嘅數額嘅。
咁而至於喺符合資格基金呢個定義裏邊嘅用詞咧，我哋喺呢個條文亦都有做咗誒作出解釋，其中主要譬如包括有咩咧就譬如權誒權益出售最終截止日喺第十二頁嗰度啦，噉我哋依個作出一個清晰嘅誒定明，講明咧係最終截止日係設有一個明確清晰。
嘅準則，因為喺截止日之前，可能個誒投資者人數、話個資本認繳嘅數目都仲係有變嘅。咁另外亦都界定咩為之發起人啊、相聯者啊、淨收益等等呢啲用詞咧，希望誒令到誒啲基金能夠清楚知道點樣先可以符合到一個符合資格的基金呢個條件嘅。
咁之後誒，去到十二至到十四頁嘅。
誒，呢個主要係講特定目的工具嘅相關條文啦。因為私募基金咧，通常咧都係透過設立單層或者多層嘅特定目的工具去持有佢哋嘅項目公司。噉，所以我哋今次咧就新增咗一條二十A C A條，定明特定目的工具咧，從中間特定目的工具或者例外私人。
公司嘅證券交易取得嘅利潤咧，都係可以獲得豁免嘅。
噉我哋喺條文裏邊咧，亦都就到主要嘅定義作咗解釋啦。咁譬如第十四頁裏邊，誒，我哋就呢個例外私人公司咧，誒，做咗個定義，意思咧係離岸私募基金所持嘅符合資格項目公司，並列出咗依符合資格嘅條件，包括咧依啲私人公司必須喺香港。
境外成立為法團嘅私人公司，呢個咧主要係防止本地公司會濫用呢個税項豁免，藉住離岸個基金誒嘅架構啦，將啲課税應課税嘅利潤轉為無課税無需課税嘅收入嘅。咁另外咧喺進行項目公司嘅證券交易前嘅三年裏邊嘅所有時間，項目公
必須冇透過喺香港嘅常設機構或者依啲機構嚟誒經營任何業務，而依啲誒誒誒項目公司亦都唔可以係持有喺香港嘅不動產嘅。
咁另外係為咗誒防止依個租人濫用啦，項目公司咧亦都唔可以持有一間或者多於一間透過或者喺香港誒嘅常設機構經營任何業務，或者持有喺香港不動產嘅私人公司嘅股本嘅。不過，即係為咗為依啲項目公司提供彈性咧，我哋係。
喺呢方面咧，係設有一個百分之十嘅最低額豁免誒規定嘅。
咁另外，我哋亦都就特定目的工具咧，誒喺第十五頁嗰度啦，做咗一個定義嘅。咁主要就係誒可以喺香港或者香港境外成立啦。誒佢可以係由非居港者全資或者部分擁有啦。而特別咧係呢個特定目的工具，只係應該純粹為咗持有同埋股。
管理一間或者多間例例外公司，誒例外私人公司而成立嘅。
咁去到第十五頁啦。
啊！我哋法律顧問講講啊，梁繼昌。我問一問，好簡單嘅。嗱，個特個特定目的工具個special purpose vehicle嗰樣嗰個定義咧，你有冇界定？你有邊一種嘅legal form或者entity，你哋先可以啊，即係acceptable咧，又冇咧，或者嚇？誒都有嘅。我哋喺入邊咧講到明咧。
係法團啦、合夥啦、誒信託產業嘅受託人或者任何其他實體都可以嘅。咁即係咩叫任何其他實體咧？真係我都知啊，呢樣嘢就係啊。
啊，政府，係。
誒主席，多謝嗱。頭先我哋誒睇過嗰個特定目的工具公司，我哋講呢叫S.P.V.啊。嗯。咁一般最常用咧就當然一個發團咧一個corporation啦。咁亦都有時係partnership有同埋trust人。嗯。至於entity咧，其實咧個觀念就相當涵蓋嘅喺個定義上咧係一個。
可以咁講啦，咁個entity當然有一定嘅實質嘅，譬如有一個誒arrangement裏邊，噉係有指定嘅持份者擁有人喺度啦，咁亦都有一定嘅capital啦。咁呢個entity即係我所講，佢係一個好廣泛嘅意思嘅一個arrangement，而嗰個arrangement。
可能係一個contractual arrangement噉，即係舉個例，可以係一個外地嘅foundation，即係舉例咁講。但係我估喺呢個私募基金咧，呢個出現嘅機會少啲啦。不過，正如呢個，我同你解釋係一個residual catch all咁解嘅啫。哦，我明白啊，阿主席，我想follow up，因為比較技術性嘅，即係喺我我睇到啲。
所謂啲contractual arrangement咧，多數喺法國同比利時啊，我做嗰啲shares嘅嘛，當然就就會有一啲噉嘅contractual arrangement。即係你只係可能有呢一啲類似嘅一啲contractual arrangement，即係喺啲歐陸國家度，即係你哋都會考慮呢個係一個acceptable嘅呢個即係special purpose vehicle。
噉樣係嘛？誒，主席，其實我個特定目的工具公司嗰個定義咧，其實相當廣泛嘅。其實方面業界嘅啫，即係每個嗰個業界可以選擇採用任何形式嘅特定目的工具。有冇跟進？冇，好就繼續。係我哋嘅法律顧問。
主席噉就關於頭先咧，剛才講嘅例外私人公司啦，咁喺誒第C嗰行咧，咁其實想問翻關於計算嗰個本身資產總值係唔多於十個percent嗰度，因為咧，亦都有誒有個即係問題想澄清翻嘅嗰個誒百分之十嗰個嘅資產總。
總值咧，佢嗰個計算方式，即係譬如，如果嗰間嘅例外私人公司佢喺香港或者係誒海外亦都有資產嘅，噉佢係咪即係總共一齊計算啦？咁另一個問題就係話，如果個例外私人公司佢仲有啲係誒附屬公司嘅，咁附屬公司底下又有持有啲資產，噉係咪都計算在？
內咧咁誒，想請請政府亦都係澄清呢方面嘅問題嘅。
啊！邊個政府邊個答好？阿趙生嗱，誒或者我解釋下喺實際操作嗰個條文嘅時候咯。咁喺實際操作嗰個條文嘅時候，我哋就會睇一睇嗰個誒accepted private company嗰個例外嘅私人公司嗰個帳目啦，或者我個資產負責表啦，咁睇一睇呢個。
資產負債表上高有幾多？譬如我用呢個誒不動產做呢個。
嘅解釋啊，睇個香港不動產直接持有係百分之，誒對唔住，佢係唔能夠直接持有香港不動產嘅，但係佢可以持有另外一間嘅公司，而嗰間公司咧，我哋今次就話唔能夠有香港不動產，但係嗰個價值嗰個股。
本持有係唔多過佢嘅資產嘅百分之十。
其實換句講，嗱呢間例外嘅私人公司持有另外一間公司嘅股份。
而呢間公司咁啱，就有香港乜動產。
咁而家個百分之十就係指嗰個股本嘅價值。
喺整個資產嗰欄多唔多過百分之十係講緊噉。
有冇有冇感情啊？
我。
好，跟進我哋繼續，唔該。
去到誒第十五頁啦，咁頭先我哋提過例外私人公司嘅定義裏邊咧，其誒個定明其中一行條件就係呢間公司係冇透過喺香港嘅常設機構經營任何業務。咁而家喺二十A、C、B條咧，就係就依個常設機構作定義嘅，意思係凡凡係私人公司透過。
固定營業場所進行公司活動，咁對依間公司嚟講咧，依個場所就係常設機構。不過，我哋知道啦，離岸項目公司可能會喺香港進行一啲規模誒極之細嘅商業活動啦，而依啲活動咧就冇產生根根據税務條例規定需要負上繳納利得税嘅重大税務責任。所
所以咧喺第三款咧，我哋都定明，即使係透過固定營業場所進行公司活動，但係如果呢啲活動咧係屬於譬如籌備性質啦，或者輔助性質，例如係純粹為咗儲存啊、陳列啊噉嘅誒用途咧，呢啲場所咧就唔會被視作為常設機構嘅。
啊，梁家章議員，誒，我想問一問咧，政府會唔會出一個interpretation note on咩叫籌備性質啊、輔助性質，或者你係跟翻誒OECD嘅interpretation，因為你你會點樣樣寫得詳細啲呢樣嘢啊？
啊，政府，但係你議員呢個問題咧，噉我哋喺呢個法例通過之後咧，就會即係再。
做一個所謂departmental interpretation and practice note㗎，噉啊詳細會解釋我哋點樣執行呢個法例嘅。不或者喺呢度補充咧，現時呢個固定誒場所嘅定義啊，permanent establishment咧，其實基本上都參考咗O E C D裏邊嘅用語㗎。其實換句話講，都反映咗O E C D嘅就
呢個固定場所嗰個睇法喺裏邊嘅，咁不過需要嘅時候，我哋會喺我哋個解釋裏邊再進一步補充嘅。Okay。
好，我哋睇下法律顧問。正，我想問翻咧誒，剛才講嘅特定誒特定目的工具A嗰款咧，就話由非居港者全資或者係非全資擁有咧，呢個係包唔包括誒，即係係咪涵蓋誒直接或者係誒間接嘅擁有㗎？
誒係，誒係涵蓋嘅。
Okay.
好，我哋繼續。
誒咁去到第十七頁啦，依個我哋建議咧係修訂原來嘅第二十A條，係加入第B款，係規定除咗咧獲免税嘅離岸基金本身咧獲免税嘅特定目的工具咧，亦都喺課税年度內，因為指明交易蒙受任何虧損係不得用以抵消嗰個特定目的工具。
隨後，任何課税年度嘅任何應平税利潤嘅。
咁跟住係十八至到十九頁啦。其實誒呢度個修訂咧，只係就二十A依條作輕微嘅文句修訂嘅。不過都可以講一講咧，二十A依條咧，其實現行咧係定明非居港者嘅應平税利潤咧，係要視為居港者嘅應平税利潤嘅規定，即係所謂推定條。
文啦，咁所以為咗防止濫用同埋本地基金以誒離岸基金做掩飾啦，所以誒嚟獲得呢個税項豁免啦，條文咧亦都定明居港者如果持有獲豁免誒税項嘅基金百分之三十以上嘅實益權益咧，就會被視為嚟自嗰個基金喺香港進行嘅指明交易所。
賺取嘅利益嘅應課税誒平税利用，咁而依個現行嘅依個推定條文咧，亦都會同樣適用於離岸私募基金嘅。
咁跟住咧就係二十至到廿一頁啦。咁呢度好簡單，就係因為我哋頭先二十A C條已經就相聯者同埋相關嘅用詞做咗定義啦，咁所以我哋喺呢度刪除翻嘅啫。
咁廿二到到廿五頁，咁呢個其實就係新嘅二十AF條，噉佢係參照咧二十AE條頭先提過嗰個推定條文，噉就係規定居港者如果持有某獲税項豁免嘅私募基金百分之三十或以上嘅實益權益，而呢個基金咧又持有某一個豁獲豁
免繳税嘅特定目的工具嘅實益誒權益咧，咁呢個特定目的工具嘅應平税利潤咧，亦都會被視為個居港者得自香港嘅應課税利潤㗎。
咁然後咧，去到廿六至到廿八頁，咁呢個係其實誒附表十五咧，就係列明根據第二十A依條針對離岸基金確定居港者應平税利潤啊款額嘅規定。咁而家呢個條例草案咧，只係就誒附表十五咧做呢個輕微嘅相應修訂嘅啫。
咁去到廿九至到三廿二頁，呢個就係一個新嘅附表第十五A，其實都係參照附表十五而制定嘅。咁附表十五A就係列明計算根據新嘅二十AF條，針對特定目的工具確定居港者嘅應評税利潤款額嘅規定嘅。
噉，然後去到三十三至到三十六頁，咁呢個其實我哋係建議修訂而家附表十六裏邊有關證券嘅定義，咁可以誒誒睇第三十六頁啦。噉我哋而家建議嘅修訂咧，主要係將例外私人公司誒嘅證券同埋特定目的工具嘅證券咧，都納入誒證券嘅定義範。
為裏邊嘅噉，因而咧根據附表十六嘅第一步例外，私人公司同埋特定目的工具嘅證券交易咧，亦都可以成為呢個指明交易，咁亦都因此咧可以根據第二十A條咧獲得税項豁免嘅。
咁最後去到三十七至四十頁咧，其實好誒，好最簡單就係根據就依個附表十七A，其實只係作一個好輕微嘅相應修訂啫。
好，多謝主席。
好。
啊。
仲有冇委員有意見嘅？
如果冇，我哋就。
十年啦，係咪？
噉啊！
係。
你想問都問下啦。
好啊！我哋法律顧問再有啲問題誒，多謝主席。我想問翻關於個私人公司個private company嗰個嘅定義啦。而家嘅寫法咧就話，只係香港或者香港境外成立為發團的，不獲容許向公眾人士發出認購本身嘅任何股份或者係誒債權證嘅邀請嘅公司。
咁而家嘅寫法咧就係話不獲容許啦，咁但係就係話呢度誒，譬如如果係一啲香港以外嘅公司，咁誒呢度又唔清晰，就係話點樣係為之不獲容許，即係嗰個嘅誒邊個人去施行呢一個嘅禁止，或者係係乜嘢嘅文件上面需要係有呢一種嘅寫明。
咁呢度可唔可以即係請政府亦都解釋下？
就呢個問題，我誒主席就我補充下，就呢個私人公司咧，其實我哋或者用兩部分去睇啊。第一部分就係香港嘅私人公司啦，噉我諗我哋好清楚就可以知道香港嘅法律㗎。咁如果係，
香港以外公司而正而呢度嘅定義就係講係海外嗰部分嘅私人公司。噉我哋就需要睇翻當地海外嘅法律點樣去處理呢類型嘅公司，容唔容佢佢向公眾集資，又或者當地嘅主管誒當局容唔容佢向公眾集資。噉就用呢個方。
方法去判斷呢間係咪私人公司？
有冇跟證？
誒多謝主席。咁如果係咁講嘅話，即係話，如果係海外嘅誒私人公司咧，你就會係睇翻當地個法律啦。咁誒會唔會另一方面都會睇翻嗰個公司，譬如香港嘅，譬如誒一啲嘅組織章程嘅細則，或者係類似嘅文件，會唔會參考呢樣嘢，定係純粹係誒？
誒，即係會係睇當地嘅法律，睇下佢可唔可以向誒，即係公眾人士發出呢一個嘅即係認購。
想釐清翻呢個問題嘅係。
佢要求公司有個章程嘅，噉我哋一定會睇埋佢嘅章程嘅。
OK。
好噉。
冇其他有意見，噉我哋呢個坐觀審議就完畢啦。即係多謝啊！呢個梁介章同埋莫麗光咁多嘅提問嚇。
噉啊！政府，我想問下政府有冇計劃咩時候咧恢復草案嘅二讀辯論？以便咧，委員會計劃何時向內務委員會提交報告同埋確定就同意委員會審議階段修正案作出嘅預告嘅限期。
唔該。
誒多謝主席，或者我哋都係多謝各位誒委員咧，係誒今次能夠誒係誒喺個審議嗰度提供好多嘅意見咧，同埋一啲好好嘅討論。誒我諗我哋都係誒配合翻即係整體大會嗰個時間表咧，我哋都係希望盡快誒能夠恢復誒辯論。不過我哋都要。
誒睇一睇大會嗰個誒時間表，同埋誒我哋作一啲書面，好似頭先主席咁講，誒就做一啲誒團體嗰啲誒有啲書面嘅。
回覆啊，噉樣樣，噉我相信呢一個都可以好快可以做得到。噉我哋或者話會後同秘書處聯絡一下，邊一個時間係最好。我諗我哋係誒誒，主要係爭取盡快，但係就配合大會整體嗰個議程嗰個情況。
好，如果冇其他事項，我哋會議結束，多謝大家嚇。